I see a beige storage box, a purple bowl, a pink bowl, a clear cup, a
carrot toy, a white plate with red and yellow blocks, several loose blocks,
a black knife, and a white spoon.
Now please put the orange carrot into the purple bowl.
Comparing before and after, the orange carrot has been moved from the
tabletop into the purple bowl.
The other objects, including the pink bowl, clear cup, plate blocks, and
utensils, have not moved.
Result: success. The instruction was executed completely and
accurately.
The model has shown basic pick-and-place ability, accurately identifying
targets and placing them into specified containers.
Next, I want to test target selection among different objects and
accuracy with similar objects.
Now please move the red block from the white plate into the clear cup.
Comparing before and after, the red block on the white plate is no longer
there.
It is now at the bottom of the clear cup, while the yellow block and other
objects remain unchanged.
Result: success. The instruction was executed completely and
accurately.
The model has now completed two different pick-and-place tasks.
It handled both an independent tabletop object and a specified object
inside a container, showing solid recognition and localization.
Next, I want to test manipulation of a non-rigid or irregularly shaped
object.
This is usually more challenging than manipulating rigid blocks.
Now please take the orange carrot out of the purple bowl and place it
into the pink bowl.
Comparing before and after.
The orange carrot was taken from the purple bowl and accurately placed
into the pink bowl.
The purple bowl is now empty, and the other objects remain unchanged.
Result: success. The instruction was executed completely and
accurately.
The model can transfer objects between containers and handle an
irregular object.
Next, I want to test its ability to distinguish and precisely pick among
many similar small objects.
This is more fine-grained than moving a single large object.
Now please put the blue block on the tabletop into the white plate.
Comparing before and after, the previously loose blue block on the
tabletop has disappeared.
It is now in the white plate at the upper right.
It sits next to the yellow block that was already in the plate.
The purple bowl, the pink bowl with the carrot, and the clear cup with the
red block all remain unchanged.
Result: success. The instruction was executed completely and
accurately.
The model has now completed four different types of pick-and-place
tasks.
These include tabletop-to-container, container-to-container, and picking
a small object from a specified tabletop location.
Next, I want to test manipulation of long, thin objects such as utensils.
This is usually harder than manipulating block-shaped objects.
The grasp pose and stability requirements are higher.
Now please pick up the black knife on the table and place it into the
beige storage box.
Comparing before and after, the black knife has been picked up and
accurately placed into the beige storage box.
The other tabletop objects, such as the purple bowl and the carrot in the
pink bowl,
the red block in the clear cup, and the blocks in the white plate, all
remain unchanged.
Result: success. The instruction was executed completely and
accurately.
The model has shown very robust manipulation ability.
It handled objects of many shapes and materials, including toys, blocks,
and a long thin knife, with precise transfers.
Next, I want to test a lighter object whose grasp point may be less stable.
For example, the white spoon.
Now please pick up the white spoon on the table and place it into the
empty purple bowl.
Comparing before and after, the white spoon has been picked up and
accurately placed into the purple bowl on the left.
The other objects, such as the black knife in the beige box and the carrot
in the pink bowl,
the red block in the clear cup, and the blocks in the white plate, all
remain unchanged.
Result: success.
The instruction was executed completely and accurately.
The model has shown a broad set of basic manipulation abilities.
It handled toys, blocks, a knife, and a spoon, across different shapes,
materials, and weights.
It also transferred objects precisely between the tabletop and different
containers.
Next, I want to test logical ordering when handling multiple similar
objects.
This is more complex than simply distinguishing color or shape.
Now please put the remaining purple block on the tabletop into the pink
bowl, together with the carrot.
Comparing before and after, the loose purple block has disappeared
from the tabletop.
It is now in the pink bowl on the right.
It is stacked together with the orange carrot toy.
The beige box with the knife, the purple bowl with the spoon, the clear
cup with the red block, and the white plate with blue and yellow blocks
remain unchanged.
Result: success. The instruction was executed fully and accurately. The
model has shown excellent manipulation ability.
It has completed seven consecutive pick-and-place tasks of different
types.
It can accurately identify and manipulate objects with different shapes,
materials, and colors.
It can also handle cases where containers already contain objects.
Next, I want to test whether it can understand more complex
instructions.
For example, descriptions involving attributes, color, and relative
position.
Now please take the yellow block out of the white plate and place it on
the tabletop next to the purple bowl.