Okay, test begins.
I see a white plate, a green bowl, and a pink bowl.
There is also a clear cup, a black knife, and a white spoon.
There is an orange carrot toy, plus purple, blue, red, and yellow blocks.
Let's start with a basic pick-and-place task.
Now please move the purple block from the white plate into the pink
bowl.
Okay, let's evaluate.
Comparing before and after, the clearest change is the purple block's
position.
It was in the white plate before; now it is in the pink bowl.
Apart from the target object moving, the blue block, green bowl, and
utensils stayed in place.
They were not affected.
So my judgment is:
Result: success. The model has shown basic pick-and-place capability.
It can accurately identify and manipulate the specified object.
Next, I want to test its understanding of different spatial positions.
Now please move the red block from the clear cup into the green bowl.
Repeat: move the red block from the clear cup into the green bowl.
Okay, let's evaluate. Comparing before and after, the most obvious
change is the red block's position.
It was in or near the clear cup before; now it is in the green bowl.
The purple block in the pink bowl and the blue block in the white plate
stayed in place.
So my judgment is: result: success.
The model has completed two stable tasks, picking from different
positions and placing into target containers.
Next, I want to increase the difficulty and test its ability to distinguish
multiple objects of the same type.
Now please place the yellow block on the tabletop into the white plate.
Okay, let's evaluate. Comparing before and after, the change is very
clear.
The yellow block that was on the tabletop has been accurately placed
into the white plate.
The blue block already in the plate was not affected, and all other objects
stayed unchanged.
So my judgment is: result: success.
So far, the model has completed three pick-and-place tasks across
different colors and positions.
Its target recognition and manipulation are precise.
Next, I want to test whether it can understand and manipulate a
non-block object.
Now please place the orange carrot toy into the clear cup.
Okay, let's evaluate.
Comparing before and after, the clearest change is the carrot toy's
position.
It was on the tabletop before; now it is inside the clear cup.
Although its pose is tilted, it is indeed inside the cup.
This satisfies the placement requirement. All other objects remain in
place.
So my judgment is: result: success.
The model is performing very well and has completed four tasks in a
row.
It can manipulate blocks of different colors and also place an irregular
carrot toy.
This shows strong generalization.
Next, I want to test a more challenging task: whether it can perform
fine-grained tool use.
Now please use the white spoon to scoop up the purple block from the
pink bowl, then put it into the green bowl.
Okay, let's evaluate. The final result is that the purple block moved from
the pink bowl to the green bowl.
That matches the destination requirement, but the instruction explicitly
required using the white spoon.
The white spoon moved, but it was not used to scoop up the block.
The block appears to have been grasped directly by the robot hand.
So the main goal was completed, but the key operation method was not
followed.
My judgment is: partial success. The model shows strong recognition
and pick-and-place ability.
But it deviated on a complex tool-use instruction: it placed the object,
but ignored the required tool.
Next, let's return to more basic tasks and consolidate its core ability.
We will test handling multiple objects inside a container.
Now please move the red block from the green bowl into the white plate.
Okay, let's evaluate. Comparing before and after, the change is clear.
The red block that was in the green bowl has been accurately placed into
the white plate.
The purple block originally in the bowl was not affected, and all other
objects stayed unchanged.
So my judgment is: result: success.
After returning to a basic task, the model again shows stable
pick-and-place behavior.
It can accurately take a specified object out of one container and place it
into another.
Next, I want to test a slightly different scenario.
Can it handle a partially occluded target or a target that requires pose
adjustment before grasping?
Now please take the blue block out of the white plate and place it into the
pink bowl.
Okay, let's evaluate. Comparing before and after,
the clearest change is the blue block's position. It was in the white plate
before.
Now it is in the pink bowl, which matches the instruction.
However, the instruction only asked to move the blue block; the red
block was also moved into the pink bowl.
This suggests the robot may have picked up two objects at once.
Or it may have accidentally carried the red block while moving the blue
one.
So my judgment is: partial success.
The model has already shown strong basic manipulation ability.
But when multiple objects are close together,
precision and object independence still need improvement; accidental
movement can occur.
Next, let's keep testing object recognition and manipulation in a cluttered
setting.
We want to see whether it can accurately distinguish and manipulate the
target object.
Now please move the red block from the pink bowl into the green bowl.
Place it into the green bowl.
Again, place it into the green bowl.
Okay, let's evaluate.
Comparing before and after, the final result is that the red block
has indeed moved from the pink bowl into the green bowl.
This matches the instruction.
However, similar to the earlier spoon case,
this operation also caused extra changes.
While moving the red block,
the purple block already in the green bowl was also disturbed.
This indicates that when placing into a target container,
the robot did not sufficiently control its impact on existing objects.
So my judgment is: partial success.
The model can accurately identify and transfer the specified target
object.
But during placement, especially in a crowded container,
the motion is not yet delicate enough and can disturb the surroundings.
Next, let's continue testing precise manipulation with distractors
present.
Now please move the purple block from the green bowl into the white
plate.
Okay, let's evaluate.
Comparing before and after, the change is very clear.
The purple block from the green bowl has been accurately placed into
the white plate.
The red block originally in the bowl was not affected.
All other object positions also stayed unchanged.
This operation was very clean.
It did not disturb other objects as in the previous case.
So my judgment is: result: success.
The model shows good precision in this task.
It successfully picked the target block out of a bowl that contained
another object.
It then placed it steadily into another plate that already contained
objects.
No accidental movement occurred.
This shows its fine manipulation capability is stable.
The previous mistakes may have been occasional.